IGO JEFERSON BARROS COELHO

AMSTERDAM - NL HET BREED, 581, 1025HV

E-mail: <u>igojeferson.coelho@gmail.com</u> https://github.com/lgoJeferson Brazilian, 30 years

Phone: +31 6 3926 6372

https://www.linkedin.com/in/igojeferson/

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I am an easy-going and enthusiastic person with a positive attitude, good professional relationships, good teamwork, and leadership sense. Building on my Knowledge and Experience is my main goal in this industry, and I am constantly hungry to know more, the fast-paced world of IT is where I belong as it provides a constant challenge. As I have also worked in highly regulated markets, I work very well under pressure and work hard to meet deadlines and bring quality products and services to my employer and clients. I enjoy troubleshooting and problem-solving; I believe this to be my strong point and find great joy in diagnosing and fixing problems. This was why I joined the great wide world of IT and will never look back. I hope to be an asset in my workplace and will strive to drive my team to do the same.

EDUCATION

- ➤ MBA Development of Java Applications SOA and IoT FIAP 2017
- > Technologist in Systems Analysis and Development FIAP 2014
- > English: Professional Proficiency
- ➤ Certificates: EX188 Red Hat Certified Specialist in Containers: 2023 | CCDAK Confluent Certified Developer for Apache Kafka: 2022 | AWS Certified Developer Associate: 2018 | OCP Java SE 7 Programmer (Oracle Certified Professional, 1Z0-804): 2016 | OCA Java SE 7 Programmer (Oracle Certified Associate, 1Z0-803): 2014 | ISTQB Certified Tester Foundation Level CTFL: 2013 |

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

❖ Senior Software Engineer

ABN Amro Clearing

08/2021 - Present Day

- Client: ABN Amro Clearing
- **Project: MAIN Market Infrastructure:** working as a Java Software Engineer on developing new features, participating in product improvement meetings, training new team members, pair-programming, constant code reviews, evangelizing good practices, also frequently engaged with day and night support to help to resolve critical incidents.
- **Project description:** It's a **financial message streaming platform** that connects 32 exchanges to AACB's IT landscape by providing reliable infrastructure and giving the internal stakeholders the information required. The purpose of the platform is to instantly provide the information to the internal systems, which then proceed with their analysis and decision-making. Robust architecture, responsible for processing more than 20 million messages/day.
- Technology Stack: Java 8, Kafka, JavaEE, Jboss, Chronicle-Map, JMS, Hazelcast, Protobuffers, Angular, Jenkins, Postgres, Flyway, Grafana, Splunk, Git, IntelliJ, Maven

Senior Software Engineer

Ilegra

07/2019 - 08/2021

- Client: Thomson Reuters
- Project: OGT Onesource Global Trade: I worked as a Java Software Engineer dealing directly with the client, understanding requirements (functional and non-functional), aligning expectations, and making design documents to be delivered to the team. Acting as an evangelizer of good practices, and as a technical reference for the development team, providing training whenever necessary.
- **Project description:** In this project, it was a modernization of a market-leading product. Where we made use of the pattern strangler, to break down the monolith into services.
- **Technology Stack:** Java, Spring Stack, AWS, GIT, Gradle, Flyway, Gatling, Kafka as messaging, Datadog for observability, Oracle as database, Ansible, Kubernetes, Cucumber, Mockito, JUnit.

- Client: Orsegups
- Project: Property security automation project, where I developed services for a security monitoring solution.

The purpose of the project involved a series of IOT devices, each with its own purpose, such as: face reading, motion sensor, vibration sensor, which generated events for our services, which could trigger alerts and a security team to take the appropriate actions, based on a series of parameterizations. My contribution to this project practically involved the development of actions based on the defined rules, all development was done in AWS

• Technology Stack: Java, Jersey, Spring Stack, AWS (SQS, SNS, S3, IoT-Core, EKS, RDS, Lambda, ELB, Route53), Bitbucket, Gradle, Flyway, Gatling, Terraform, Bash, Packer, Kubernetes

❖ Senior Software Engineer

Engineering do Brasil

07/2018 - 07/2019

- **Description:** Development in the area of Digital Innovation, working with a team that brings new technologies to the company ecosystem, according to the needs and possibilities are given by the business. I work very focused on making proofs of concepts on new technologies, such as chatbot, integrations on Facebook, google maps, GCP ml, and I also had contact with ionic for hybrid applications. I also worked in a Digital Platform, that has in the core some integrations like CRM, Internal Microservices, Orders, Payments, Product Catalog. Supporting new developers as a technical reference for the project, establishing patterns, and mentoring.
- Technology Stack: Java, Spring Stack, Maven, Git, Kong API Gateway, Apigee, ELK, Docker Swarm, RabbitMQ, GCP.

❖ Medior Java Software Developer

5aattiva

06/2017 - 06/2018

- Client: Serasa Experian
- **Description:** Development of java services focused mainly on integrations with Serasa Experian's internal services, integrations such as payment services such as credit card and invoice, AWS S3, and Sendgrid for emails. Delivered quality applications under the schedule, even under adverse conditions, such as tight schedules and loss of key resources.
- Technology Stack: Java, Spring Stack, QueryDSL, Maven, Git, Oracle, Redis, H2, JUnit, Mockito, PowerMock, Jacoco, AWS (Elastic Beanstalk).
- Client: Editora Abril
- Description: Working on the development of a complete solution for the logistics operation of publications.
- Technology Stack: Java, Spring Stack, Angular2, Mysql, CouchDB, VRAPTOR4, RabbitMQ, Maven, Git.

❖ Medior Java Software Developer

Vector ITC

09/2015 - 06/2017

- Client: <u>Tokio Marine Seguradora</u>
- **Description:** Work on the developer team in the improvement and maintenance of Corporate Insurance Systems. Using Scrum as a method of working
- Technology Stack: Java 7, Spring MVC, JdbcTemplate, JSTL, SVN, Tomcat, Oracle, PLSQL.
- Client: Banco Santander
- **Description:** Project: FEP Firmas e Poderes The main developer focused on improving the performance of a web application that serves the entire country, part of the work was dedicated to identifying performance improvements in services and procedures (PLSQL). I also worked on the development of new features with great use of mainframe integrations.
- **Technology Stack:** Java, Spring MVC, JSF with Primefaces, JPA with Hibernate, Websphere, Tomcat, IBM Websphere Message Queue, Oracle, IReport, JasperReports.

DETRAN / BA - Public School of Traffic | Regional Action Company / BA - Cistern Management System

- **Description:** Development and analysis of projects using Java. Assistance in the development of methodology for agile software development and implementation of testing methodology.
- Technology Stack: Java, JSP, Servlets, Eclipselink, JUnit, Selenium, Tomcat, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Maven, Jenkins, Sonar, JSF 2.1, EJB 3.1, Hibernate, Jboss 7, Android, Web Services (JAX-WS)

OTHER EXPERIENCES (2010 to 2014)

❖ Tester and Quality Assurance: Pruvo Informática Itda 09/2013 -09/2014

♦ Administrative Technical Support: LAFER 07/2013 - 09/2013

♦ Administrative Assistant: LAFER 10/2010 - 07/2013

Coursework

[➤] Kubernetes Installation and Configuration Fundamentals - Pluralsight: 2021 | Apache Kafka Series - Learn Apache Kafka for Beginners v2 - Udemy: 2020 | Gatling Fundamentals for Stress, Load & Performance Testing - Udemy: 2020 | Docker from A to Z™: Swarm + Jenkins - Udemy: 2019 | AWS Certified Developer Associate - Udemy: 2019 | Developing Applications with Google Cloud Platform - Coursera: 2019 | Getting Started with Google Kubernetes Engine - Coursera: 2018 | Building Web Applications with the new Angular4 - Udemy: 2017 | Architecture and Design of Java Project - Caelum: 2016 | TOGAF Foundation - Level 1 - FIAP: 2015 | Envisioning Big Data - FIAP: 2015 | Wildfly 8 - High Performance Cluster Management in a DevOps Environment - 4Linux: 2014